

John Eliades

Electrical and Computer Engineering University of Thessaly, Volos

• Marousi, Athens, Greece

→ +30-6970630050

johneliades@hotmail.com
Project Showcase
GitHub
LinkedIn

SUMMARY

With many years of hands-on experience as a software developer, particularly through personal programming projects, I'm excited about the opportunity to bring my skills to real-world projects and make a significant impact. My journey has demonstrated my ability to consistently deliver results, and I am enthusiastic about continuing this path, making a meaningful difference with my dedication and expertise.

EDUCATION

• University of Thessaly, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering(B.Sc & M.Eng)

Thesis: Torrent client in Go programming language.

2016-2021 GPA: 8.0/10.0

Professional Experience

• Coding Instructor

2019-Present

Self Employed

- ➤ Delivered personalized instructions to many students, both individually and in group settings, tailoring sessions to each student's unique learning style and designed hands-on coding projects that allowed them to apply theoretical knowledge in practical, real-world scenarios.
- ➤ Covered programming fundamentals to build a strong foundation, including concepts, syntax, algorithms, and problem-solving. Courses primarily utilized the C and Java programming languages, covering topics such as string manipulation, lists, trees, recursion, file handling, sockets, pipes, macros, processes, threads and object-oriented programming.
- ➤ Offered mentorship extending beyond coding, sharing industry insights and best practices

• System Administrator

2022-2023

Mandatory Military Service

Kos

My duties included the development, administration, operation and maintenance of the IT systems of the 80th National Guard Higher Command headquarters, as well as the units and subunits of the formation. Specifically:

- ➤ Performed backup, formatting, and OS re-installation on numerous computers, reintegrating them into the Active Directory with the appropriate IP configuration and security permissions.
- ➤ Managed user account administration of Windows Server clients.
- ➤ Identified and replaced defective hardware components in numerous critical computers, resolving issues such as bluescreens and non-bootable machines.
- ➤ Safely transferred critical files from the internet to the army's intranet.

Personal Projects

To explore each project in detail, please click on the project titles. You'll be directed to the respective project's github page for a deeper dive into my work.

• Asynxy: Asynchronous RCE middleware webapp

2019

Created a webapp for remote command execution to a set of slave nodes, who periodically request new commands, execute them locally and post results back to the application using an http rest api.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Node.js, Express, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, MongoDB, MariaDB

• Windows Server 2019 2019

Automation of mass user creation on a Windows Server 2019 with group policy (GPO) restrictions on the clients adequate for use in a school environment.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Batch

• Portfolio 2019

A responsive website used as a portfolio depicting my projects, events I have participated in, and the skills acquired in the process.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS

• File Explorer 2020

A file explorer that achieves cross-platform functionality in a visually appealing way.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Java, Swing

• Code Crawler 2020

A crawler that finds the answer to any software-related question by searching for accepted answers in popular sites such as StackOverflow.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, Google API, BS4

• Portal 2020

A recreation of the teleportation mechanics of the popular game Portal.

➤ Tools & technologies used: UE5, C++, Blender

• Chess Analyzer 2022

A script that finds the on-screen chessboard, runs a custom made image classification Keras model to identify the pieces and then highlights the best move using the latest local version of Stockfish while also providing a lichess link for further GUI analysis.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, Keras, Stockfish API

• Village Movies Crawler

A script that uses the village cinemas reverse engineered WebTicketing API to retrieve a list of currently playing movies and the ticket availability and showtimes, and sorts them according to IMDB rating.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, WebTicketing API, BS4

EVENTS

• Panoptis - Military Cybersecurity exercise

2019 Volos

2023

➤ Our team at University of Thessaly solved and reported on Data Exfiltration, and Social Network Communication Analysis episodes.

• Deloitte Hacking Challenge - CTF Cybersecurity contest

2019

➤ Finalist, finishing 23rd out of 175 participants (40 participants in the final round) after solving various Athens problems including web exploitation, reverse engineering, scripting, steganography etc.

• Google Hashcode 2020

2020

➤ Solved the challenge using a relatively efficient greedy algorithm.

Volos

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Go, Python, Bash, Matlab, R

• Frameworks: Express, Flask

• Other: HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, LaTeX

• Databases: MySQL, PostGreSQL, MongoDB

• Experience with various pentesting and reconnaissance security tools.

LANGUAGES

• Greek: Native language

• English: C2 level ECPE certificate of Michigan University.